你講的是法律
You're parsing the law.
我講的則是精神層面的法則
And I'm talking about a spiritual code.
保密協議是一份契約
Confidentiality is a covenant.
不僅在我和接受我諮詢的人之間成立
Not only between myself and those I counsel,
在我自己和上帝之間也成立
but also between myself and the Lord.
拉金博士  我現在重點關注的是洗錢案
Dr. Larkin, my chief focus here is the money laundering.
如果總統先生提到過馮山德
If the President brought up Xander Feng,
雷蒙德·塔斯克  還有阿道希賭場
Raymond Tusk, the Adohi Casino--
不管重點是什麼
It doesn't matter what the focus is.
我都不能向你透露私人談話的內容
I can't share anything we discussed privately.
宗教指導受法律保護
Religious guidance is protected.
但你也提供專業的心理諮詢
But you were also conducting professional therapy.
這我從未承認過
I never claimed that.
基斯先生及太太已經證實了
Mr. And Mrs. Keith confirmed as much.
我們是去了他們家
We were at their house.
但他們並沒有參與談話
But they didn't participate in any of our conversations.
他們又怎麼可能知道
So how would they know?
你是說你只提供宗教諮詢嗎
So you're saying you only gave religious counsel?
這是我對我工作的理解
That's how I choose to interpret it.
總統夫婦從沒去過你的教堂
The President and his wife have never once attended your church.
甚至都和你不是一個教派的
They're not even the same denomination.
無關緊要
Irrelevant.
法律上可緊要得很
Not legally speaking.
我絕對能說服法官發傳票給你
I'm certain I can convince a judge to issue a subpoena
因為你並非總統夫婦正式的宗教導師
on the grounds that you weren't their legitimate spiritual advisor.
那是你的特權
Which is your prerogative.
但我會上訴  我肯定會
But I can appeal. And I would.
那你一定敗訴
You'd lose.
除非對方放棄保密權利
The only circumstance by which I would talk
我絕不會回答你的問題
is if someone personally waived their privilege.
否則我寧可被判蔑視法庭
Otherwise I'd rather face contempt of court.
這事關道德
It's a matter of ethics.
總統先生  你又把沙袋挪回來了
Mr. President. Ah, you brought it back in.
弗洛伊德·梅威瑟[著名拳擊手]今早來白宮參觀
Floyd Mayweather visited the White House this morning.
我覺得他看見這個肯定很興奮
I thought he'd get a kick out of it.
他沒打幾拳
Did he have a go at it?
他打了套組合拳  我都擔心把沙袋打爆了
He threw a combination I thought would bust the stitching loose.
那場面一定很好看
Well, that must have been a treat to watch.
他告訴我  這不僅僅是力量的問題
He was telling me it's not just about the power.
比他更有力量的拳手不少
Plenty of boxers are more powerful than he is.
關鍵是他的戰術  他的準頭和速度
No, it's his tactics, his precision, his speed.
最重要的一點  就是他的反擊
Most important? His counter punch.
他躲閃騰挪  選擇最完美的時機一拳制勝
He dances and dodges and then picks the perfect moment to strike.
聽著耳熟嗎
Does that sound familiar?
什麼意思  先生
How do you mean, sir?
你送我這個沙袋  作為友誼的表示
You gave this to me as a gesture of friendship.
但我現在看著它  卻感受不到友誼
When I look at this now, I don't see friendship.
我看到的是算計
I see calculation.
你算計我  弗蘭克
You set me up, Frank.
什麼
What?
你的私下接觸  還有特別檢察官
Your back channeling. The special prosecutor.
再想想雷蒙德  琳達  還有吉姆·馬修斯
When I think about Raymond, about Linda, about Jim Matthews...
你想錯了  先生
You are wrong, sir.
這是鄧巴就婚姻諮詢問的問題
Questions from Dunbar about the marriage counseling.
"那是大海里的一根針  還不是鄧巴要找的那根"
"It's a needle in the haystack she's not trying to find."
這是你的原話  她還真就撈著了
That's what you said. Well, she found the needle.
我非常震驚  我絕沒
I am shocked, sir. I -- I never --
你震驚才怪  你想削弱我的權威
Like hell you are. You want to deminish me.
削弱你的權威
Diminish you?
為你2016年挑戰我打基礎
Laying the groundwork for a challenge in 2016.
恕我無禮  但你這論調太荒唐了
I am sorry to have to say this, sir, but you are being ludicrous.
你真以為我瞎了嗎
Do you really think I'm so blind?
從沒有哪個副總統挑戰過在位總統
A vice president has never challenged a sitting president.
你往上爬的過程中已經做過不少別人不會做的事了
You've climbed the ladder doing things other men would never do.
全都是為了服務於你和本黨的利益
Always in service to you and the party.
交出行程記錄是你的主意
It was you idea to hand over those logs.
是你讓白宮和中國扯上了關係  還有賭場
You connected the White House to China, the casino --
是雷蒙德·塔斯克讓我們與中國和賭場扯上了關係
Raymond Tusk entangled us with China and the casino.
要不是我及時干預
And if I hadn't intervened --
你沒有弗洛伊德那套騰挪的本事  我識破你了
You can't dodge and duck like Floyd. I've learned your moves now.
當了總統就易多疑  你別這樣  先生
This office breeds paranoia. Don't give into it, sir.
要不是會引人非議  我就會要求你辭職了
I'd ask for your resignation if it wouldn't make things worse.
但從此刻開始  我不想聽你的任何建議
But from this moment forward, I don't want to hear your voice,
也不想看見你
I don't want to see your face.
再讓我看見你  我就讓你吃不了兜著走
And if I do, I will put you on your god damn back.
我被驅逐了  我成功將總統和其他人隔開
Exile. I've managed to isolate the president from everyone.
包括我自己
Including myself.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
翻譯 章魚X   衛老哥   艾瑞卡
翻譯 盧克·天意   冬麟   某豚   香茗小焙
藍光版調整  timhal@HDWinG字幕組   後期 餓得慌
顧問 老杜   校對 草草   總監 草草
本字幕由YYETS翻譯 HDWinG字幕組修正 請勿去掉製作者資訊
《紙牌屋》
第二季  第十二集
"夏普女眾議員淋漓盡致地展現了
"Congresswoman Sharp is a  perfect example
軍方是如何將我們洗腦
of how the military brainwashes us
從而絕對服從黨派路線的
into never questioning the party line.
她對法案的反對是可恥的
Her opposition to the bill is disgraceful.
這會使數以千計的男性和女性
It will cost thousands of men and women
得不到他們應得的公正
the justice they deserve,
甚至會毀掉一些人的生活"
and some of them their lives."
這都是梅根·漢納希的話  他們有失公正
Those are Megan Hennessey's words. They're biased.
這是克萊爾教她說的  漢納希不過是傳聲筒
They're Claire's words. Hennessey's just the mouthpiece.
為什麼文中還說我拒絕置評
Why does it say here that I declined to comment?
你說過  會惹麻煩的事能躲就躲
You said you didn't want to kick up dust if we could avoid it.
這是《紐約時代雜誌》  你應該告訴我的
It's the New York fucking Times. You should've let me know.
是我的決定  我承擔責任
That was my call. I'll take the blame.
查明漢納希接下來會在哪裡出現
Find out when Hennessey's next appearance is.
我要搞垮這個婊子
I'm gonna beat this bitch down.
我知道她針對你  但是針對她的話...
I know she went after you, but going after her is --
不是她  是克萊爾·安德伍德
Not her. Claire Underwood.
我知道加勒特可能會產生誤解
I understand how Garrett might misconstrue things,
畢竟現在他壓力很大
given the pressure he's under.
但你肯定不會相信吧
But you can't honestly believe it yourself.
我已經不知道該相信什麼了
I don't know what to believe anymore.
弗蘭西斯非常沮喪  他只是想幫忙
Francis is devastated. All he wants to do is help,
但他覺得自己受到了冤枉
but he feels like he's being unfairly accused.
我也不想相信  克萊爾  但加勒特確信不疑
I don't want to believe it, Claire, but Garrett is convinced.
你能跟他談談嗎
Will you talk to him?
我現在得集中精力維護我的家庭
I have to concentrate on keeping my family together right now.
而不是跟他爭吵關於...
Not getting into arguments over --
如果弗蘭西斯真有什麼圖謀
If Francis were really up to something,
那他怎麼不直接把諮詢的事告訴鄧巴
don't you think he would have told Dunbar about the therapy?
他逼我們交出記錄就等於那麼做了
He basically did by forcing us to hand over the logs.
那是你丈夫的決定
Your husband chose to hand them over.
如果他拒絕  弗蘭西斯是不會逼他的
If he'd said no, Francis wouldn't have pressed the issue.
我不想跟你爭這個  克萊爾
I don't want to debate this with you, Claire.
我只求你好好想想這件事  特莉莎
All I'm asking is that you really think this through, Tricia.
他現在跟你在一起嗎
Is he with you right now?
誰
Who?
弗蘭克
Frank.
不  只有我和你
No. It's just you and me.
我要掛電話了
I want to get off the phone.
拜託你跟加勒特談談好嗎
Will you please talk to Garrett?
再見  克萊爾
Goodbye, Claire.
你怎麼看
What do you think?
我不覺得她會拋開丈夫站在我這邊
I don't think she's going to side with me instead of her husband.
除了跟你  特莉莎還跟別人說過阿普唑侖的事嗎
Did Tricia tell anyone else about the Xanax besides you?
鎮靜抗焦慮藥
應該沒有  她對此非常敏感
I doubt she would. She's very sensitive about it.
她要是跟別人說過  我們就可以把訊息傳出去
If she'd only told someone else, then we could just leak it.
但是這太明顯了
But it'll be too obvious.
醫生
The doctor.
他在保護他們  他什麼都不會說的
He's protecting them. He won't say anything.
除非他們放棄保密特權
Unless they waive the privilege.
那對他們可沒有好處
They have absolutely nothing to gain by that.
但是對我們有
But we do.
你得去見塔斯克
You have to meet with Tusk.
我背叛了他  他為什麼還要見我
Why would he talk to me after I back-stabbed him?
正因為如此他才會見你
That's precisely why he'll talk to you.
我不能去聖路易斯  你知道的...
Well, I can't go to St. Louis. You know --
塔斯克會來東部  你要做的就是找到他
Tusk will come east. Your job is to get in the same room with him.
-什麼計劃    -雷米·丹頓
- What's the play?   - Remy Danton.
去  讓杜蘭特來找我
Go. Get me Durant, in person.
我來安排
I'll set it up.
道格  一定確保其他方面我們萬無一失
And Doug? Let's make sure we're airtight on everything else.
不能有軟肋
No Achilles heel.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
"災難來臨了"  用混亂對抗混亂的人說
"Cry, 'Havoc,'" Said he who fought chaos with chaos,
"讓我們釋放戰爭惡魔"
"And let slip the dogs of war."
失約  數週不聯絡  你知道規矩
Missed appointments. No contact in weeks. You know the rules.
我要跟格林特工談
I'd like to speak to Agent Green, please.
你想幹什麼
What are you up to?
給格林打電話
Put Green on the fucking line, please.
不管你想說什麼  都可以跟我說
Anything you have to say, you can discuss it with me.
我要說的事遠遠超出了你的級別
What I have to say is way above your pay grade.
我怎麼關掉這破玩意
Where do I turn off this shit?
看看左邊的那塊螢幕
Look at the other screen, to the left.
這是什麼
What is this?
這是美國電話電報公司八個資料中心的訪問網格
That is the access grid to all eight of AT&T's data centers.
所以你還是解開手銬
So what do you say you un-cuff me
然後告訴格林特工我在等他的電話吧
and tell Agent Green I'll be waiting for his call?
我正在試圖修復與中國的關係
I'm trying to repair relations with China.
給馮政治庇護就是一記耳光
Giving Feng asylum would be a slap in the face.
加勒特有麻煩  他得表現出決心
Garrett's in trouble. He needs to appear resolute.
我們的總統有多強  我們就有多強
We're only as strong as the president we serve.
我們必須拯救他
We have to rescue him.
你怎麼能確定他的證詞不會扯上白宮
How can you be sure his testimony won't implicate the White House?
他知道誰有奶  誰是娘
He knows where his bread is buttered.
你這不是要拯救總統
This isn't about you saving the president.
-當然是    -這不是第一次了  弗蘭克
- Of course it is.   - We've been down this road before, Frank.
邁克爾·科恩  亞當·嘉樂威
Michael Kern, Adam Galloway.
我想當國務卿
I wanted to become secretary of state
是為了進行有成效的外交
in order to engage in productive diplomacy,
而不是全職損失控制
not full-time damage control.
所以我們要讓加勒特回到正軌
Which is why we have to put Garrett back on his feet.
你是想讓他脫軌吧  弗蘭克
You want him on his ass, Frank.
是總統這麼跟你說的嗎
Is this what the president told you?
他現在太多疑了  凱茜
He's paranoid, Cathy.
他想讓大家跟我反目
He's trying to turn people against me.
是你自己的行為讓大家跟你反目
You're turning them against yourself.
你在要求我坑害總統
You're asking me to undermine the president.
好吧
All right.
假如總統對我的指責屬實
Let's say that what the President has accused me of is true.
這就真的很糟嗎  考慮一下這麼做的結果
Would that be so bad? If taken to its conclusion?
對你沒有好處嗎
Wouldn't you stand to benefit?
對國家沒有好處嗎
Wouldn't the country?
我不想牽扯進去
I don't want anything to do with this.
就再做一次  凱茜
Just one more time, Cathy.
別去管那些條條框框
Let's unshackle ourselves.
機會只有一次  馮先生
This is a one-time offer, Mr. Feng.
我要白紙黑字寫下來  不加任何條件
I would need it in writing. Open-ended, no restrictions.
法定豁免權也是一樣
The same goes for legal immunity.
首先我要確認
First I need to know whether or not
你是否通過拉尼根的賭場洗錢
you funneled money through Lanagin's casino.
不  等我安全抵達美國
No, no. I will speak freely once I've arrived safely
我才會全盤托出
in the United States.
除非你現在就能提供確鑿證據
Unless you provide valuable evidence now,
司法部長不會答應任何豁免權
the attorney general will not grant immunity on any level.
我在中國已經全部否認了這些指控
I've denied these allegations in China.
我的敵人想置我於死地
My enemies want me dead.
你這是逼我給他們證據
You're asking me to give them confirmation.
作為回報  我們會給你提供避難所
And we're giving you safe haven in return.
我在迪拜已經有避難所了
I already have safe haven in Dubai.
你在那裡的庇護所只是暫時的
Your asylum there is only temporary.
我們給你提供的是永久身份
We're offering you permanent status.
我相信他們也會給我永久身份
I'm confident that they will grant me permanent status.
是外交部長親口跟你說的嗎
Did you hear that directly from the Minister of Foreign Affairs?
因為我剛跟他談過
Because I just spoke to him.
現在你連護照都沒有
Right now you are a man without a passport.
北京方面還沒查封的資產
Whatever assets Beijing hasn't seized are frozen
也都被所有和中美關繫緊密的國家凍結了
in every country with close ties to the United Sates or China,
基本上是全世界所有國家
which is just about every country in the world.
你想要自由和金錢  我們想要資訊
You want your freedom and fortune. We want information.
馮先生
Mr. Feng?
你想知道什麼
What do you need to know?
向我證實確實有洗錢行為
Confirm for me the existence of a money-laundering scheme.
是的  我們用賭場來掩飾外資流入
Yes. We used the casino to mask foreign contributions.
好的
All right.
你們中誰跟我講講這是怎麼回事
One of you want to tell me what this is all about?
你必須得遵從
You have to comply.
你是說我得出席
You mean I have to show up.
除非我們上訴
Unless we appeal.
我們會輸
We'd lose.
她要不是證據確鑿
She wouldn't have issued the subpoena
也不會傳喚我
unless she had something substantial.
我同意
I agree.
這就是為什麼我覺得你該去
Which is why I think you should go
並拒不解釋
and plead the Fifth.
你覺得她手上有什麼
What do you think she has?
我不想妄加推斷
I don't want to speculate.
老天  我付給你們六個一天的錢
God damn it, I pay the six of you more in one day
比供個孩子上大學都多
than it costs to put a kid through college.
我請你們是要你們比我知道得多
And I pay you to know more than I do.
她問詢時說的對我們會很有幫助
Her line of questioning will tell us a lot.
萬一她真要提出指控  我們可以據此準備辯護
We can use that to prepare our defense in case there's an indictment.
我什麼時候走
When do I have to go?
你的會面是在後天
Your interview is the day after next.
48小時
48 hours?
發動不了嗎
Having trouble starting it?
是的  可能電池沒電了吧
Yeah. I think the battery might be dead.
如果你想試試跨接啟動  我有電線
I have some cables if you want to try and jump it.
這真的不麻煩嗎
You sure you don't mind?
一點也不
Not at all.
好吧  你真是太好了
All right. It's really nice of you.
開引擎蓋  我把我車開過來
Pop your hood. I'll bring my car around.
好
Sure.
這位是彼得  他開車送我回來的
This is Peter. He's the guy who drove me back.
這些要放哪
Where do you want these?
我來拿  謝謝
I'll take 'em. Thanks.
瑞秋  是嗎
Rachel, right?
是的
Yeah.
麗薩說你倆是室友
Lisa said you two were roommates.
要我給你拿點什麼  來杯水嗎
Can I get you something? A glass of water?
不用  謝謝  我得走了
No, thanks. I should really get going.
好吧  太謝謝你了
All right. I can't thank you enough.
不客氣  希望車能修好
My pleasure. Good luck with the car.
謝謝
Thanks.
希望只是電池沒電  晚安
I hope it's only a dead battery. Have a good night.
我們應該給他些錢
We should give him some money.
彼得
Peter.
她得離開
She needs to be gone.
你跟我說她可以留下的
Y-- you told me she could stay.
我改主意了
I changed my mind.
你說你不在乎她在不在這兒
But you said you didn't care if she was here --
我不需要解釋什麼
I don't need to explain myself.
你受不了了  是嗎
You can't stand it, can you?
受不了我愛上了別人
The idea that I might actually love somebody.
受不了我生命中除了你還有別人
That I might have somebody in my life who isn't you.
如果你在乎她  就讓她走  瑞秋
If you care about her, make it happen, Rachel.
沒事吧
Is everything okay?
沒事  告訴你朋友我不會要錢的
Yeah. You need to tell your friend that I won't take any money.
我很樂意幫忙
I was happy to do it.
我們都需要好心人幫忙
We all need a good Samaritan every now and again.
麥金尼斯將軍被判處
Did you feel justice was served
四十年有期徒刑時  你覺得正義得到伸張了嗎
when General McGinnis got sentenced to 40 years?
梅根·漢納希  反性侵活動分子
就他的罪行而言  正義是得以伸張了
Yes, as far as his crimes go.
但還有成千的服役士兵沒有...
But not for thousands of servicemen and --
抱歉  抱歉打斷你的講話
I'm -- I'm sor-- I'm sorry to interrupt.
我的製作人告訴我
m-- my producer is telling me that,
傑奎琳·夏普剛打電話來
Jacqueline Sharp has called in,
眾議院多數黨黨鞭  議員女士  您在嗎
the house majority whip. C-- congresswoman, are you there?
是的  我在  克里斯  謝謝你接我的電話
Yes, I'm here, Chris. And thank you for taking my call.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你好  梅根
Hello, Megan.
議員女士
Congresswoman.
首先  作為一名老兵
First of all, as a veteran like yourself,
我想感謝你對國家的貢獻
I want to thank you for your service to our country.
這是責任  無需感謝
Duty doesn't require thanks.
我很高興你提到責任這個話題
I'm glad you brought up duty,
因為你最近將它稱之為洗腦
because you recently equated it with brainwashing.
那不是我的本意
That's not what I meant.
你說"緊跟黨派路線"
You said "Toeing the party line."
電話連線  傑奎琳·夏普議員  眾議院多數黨黨鞭
我的本意是文化和體系是...
What I meant was that the culture and the system is one that --
我不是打電話來和你辯論的  梅根
I didn't call to argue with you, Megan.
恰恰相反
The opposite.
我們要解決這個問題  就必須找到共同點
We can't fix this problem until we find some common ground.
你不覺得嗎
Wouldn't you agree?
就我來看這個問題沒有妥協空間
There is no middle ground as far as I'm concerned.
軍隊需要改變
The military needs to change --
你和我都曾經在軍中服役
Can't we agree that you and I served
以保護人民自由辯論的權利
so that we could protect open debate,
而這正是民主的基礎  你說不是嗎
which is the very bedrock of democracy?
理論上是的  但這不是我要說的
Yes, in theory, but that's not what I'm talking about.
不是理論上  是實際上
Not in theory. In reality.
勇敢的人為了這份自由不惜犧牲生命
Brave men and women die fighting for that freedom.
勇敢的涵義就是為那些和你意見相左的人
The meaning of bravery is fighting for the freedom
也同樣享有自由而戰鬥
of those with whom you disagree.
當然  但我們回到真正的話題上來好嗎
Sure, but let's get back to the issue here.
我認為不勇敢的人是克萊爾·安德伍德
What I don't think is brave is Claire Underwood
逃避這場辯論  找你替她進行這場鬥爭
dodging this debate and having you fight this battle for her instead.
不是這樣的
That's not true.
那我為什麼在和你而不是她談話  這是她的法案
Then why am I talking to you instead of her? It's her bill.
不只是她  是我們共同的成果
It's not just hers. It's all of ours.
可是你勇敢地說出來了
Except one of you is brave enough to say it,
而她卻是個懦夫
and the other is a coward.
安德伍德夫人勇敢地
Mrs. Underwood was brave enough
在全國性電視節目上承認她...
to go on national television and admit that she --
沒錯  但那之後她去哪了
Yeah, and where has she been since then?
應付醜聞  躲避媒體
Deflecting scandal and hiding from the press.
梅根  你在《紐約時代雜誌》上說我可恥
You called me disgraceful in The New York Times, Megan,
你當然有這個權利
and you have every right.
但我也有權說  安德伍德夫人是可恥的
But I also have the right to say that Mrs. Underwood is disgraceful,
因為沒有什麼
because there is nothing
比當逃兵更可恥
more disgraceful than running from a battle.
梅根  我們根本沒有...
Megan? That is -- we're not even...
我們馬上回來
We'll be right back.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去國會
To the Capitol.
馮提到我或總統了嗎
Did Feng mention either me or the president?
鄧巴不肯說
Dunbar wouldn't say.
但馮確認了洗錢行為
But the fact that Feng confirmed the money laundering
這足以讓白宮更受關注
increases focus on the White House.
反正我們是清白的
Well, as long as we're innocent, which we are.
雷蒙德·塔斯克被傳喚了
Raymond Tusk has been subpoenaed.
你為什麼找我們見面  比爾
Why did you ask for this meeting, Bill?
就為了向我們通報訊息嗎
Just keeping us in the loop?
是你讓國務卿杜蘭特給予馮政治庇護嗎
Did you encourage Secretary Durant to offer Feng asylum?
比爾  我的天吶
Bill, for god sakes.
總統也可能問我這個問題
The president could have asked me that question himself.
作為白宮顧問  這是我的責任
As the White House counsel, it is my responsibility --
不  我沒有
No, I did not.
那麼這是杜蘭特自己的主意嘍
So you're saying Durant acted of her own accord.
我不知道她的動機是什麼
I have no idea what her motivations were.
我和總統一樣感到震驚
I'm just as shocked as the president
她居然沒經過他本人允許就擅自而為了
that she would have gone through with this without his direct approval.
還有一個問題我想和你談談
There's another matter I'd like to discuss.
如果可以  最好只跟你談
Privately, if we could.
讓我們單獨待會兒
Just give us a few moments.
-諮詢    -是的
- The therapy.- Yes.
具體說  就是放棄保密權
To be specific, the confidentiality waiver.
馮的證詞把我們推到一個非常尷尬的位置上
Feng's testimony puts us in a very awkward position.
我們現在面對放棄保密權的極大壓力
We're under a great deal of pressure to waive the privilege.
如果不放棄  就相當於總統
If we don't, it implies that the president
承認了他沒做過的事
may have confessed to things he didn't.
鄧巴只是在瞎猜  別讓步
Dunbar is just grasping. Don't give in.
我不想讓步
I don't want to.
但拉金宗教指導保密協議的說法並不可靠
But Larkin's argument for spiritual confidentiality is shaky at best.
我們想控制事態的發展
We want to control how this thing plays out.
我能幫什麼忙
How can I help?
我們要確保不會再節外生枝
We need to know if anyone else might pop out of the woodwork.
我沒對任何人說過  克萊爾也沒說過
Well, I haven't mentioned it to anyone, and neither has Claire.
我不會辜負總統對我的信任
I would never betray the president's trust like that.
謝謝你抽出時間
Thank you for your time.
告訴總統  我非常難過
Tell the president it saddens me that
我們現在只能通過律師交流
we now have to communicate through lawyers.
要是他想親自
I will make myself available
和我談談  我會抽出時間的
if he wants to discuss any of this in person.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
梅根的話太過分了
What Megan said was offensive.
她不該質疑你的品行
She shouldn't have questioned your character.
那都是精心準備的談話要點  而且不是她準備的
Those were talking points. Carefully crafted, and not by her.
我不是來挑釁的  傑姬  我是來解決問題的
I'm not here to pick a fight, Jackie. I'm here to end one.
只要法案進行投票  這事就會結束
Well, it'll end soon enough when the bill goes to the floor.
不會進行投票的
It won't go to the floor.
我跟艾琳·布魯克斯談過了  我要撤銷法案
I've spoken to Elaine Brooks and I'm withdrawing the bill.
你說的有一定道理
What you said had some truth.
之前你提出
And early on you offered
我們一起找個折中的辦法
to sit down with me and find a middle ground.
我那時拒絕了你
I decided to draw a line in the sand.
但勇敢的做法應該是
And the braver thing would've been for me
收起我的驕傲  跟你好好談
to swallow my pride and sit down with you.
如果你還願談  我想重新開始
If you're still open to that, I'd love to start over.
你和弗蘭克在打什麼主意嗎
Are you and Frank up to something?
一項能通過的法案
A passable bill.
他讓南茜監視我  他把我的個人生活搞得
He had Nancy spy on me. He brought my personal life into --
弗蘭西斯習慣了事事得逞
Francis is used to getting his way.
他會不惜一切確保成功
And he'll do anything to make sure he does,
尤其是對我重要的事
especially if it's something important to me.
我不知道  克萊爾  我很懷疑
I don't know, Claire. I'm skeptical.
之前那樣對待你  我們深表歉意
We're deeply sorry for the way we've treated you
我們想重拾失去的信任
and we want to rebuild the trust we've lost.
你覺得這可能嗎
Do you think that's possible?
很抱歉突然這麼來了  我打過電話
I'm sorry to ambush you. I tried calling.
你不能這麼對我  克萊爾
You can't do this to me, Claire.
我說得很清楚  我必須尊重加勒特的意願
I was very clear that I have to respect Garrett's wishes --
不是那個  是性侵犯法案
Not that. The sexual assault bill.
不會進行投票了
It's not going to a vote.
議長從日程中刪除了嗎
Did the speaker remove it from the docket?
不  是我撤掉了  我剛跟傑姬談過
No. I did. I just spoke to Jackie.
是因為她那樣說你嗎
This is because of what she said about you?
我主要是擔心她接下來會不會對付你
My main concern is that she doesn't come after you next.
你和加勒特接受調查期間絕不能發生這種事
Not while you and Garrett are going through the investigation.
我想來告訴你
I thought you should be aware
因為我知道這項法案對你有多重要
because I know how much this bill meant to you.
你為法案投入了那麼多
All the work you've put in.
我們都投入過  但我們要通過傑姬的法案
That we've put in. But we'll pass Jackie's version,
邁出這一小步  循序漸進
take this baby step, and build on it.
法案的事我很失望
I'm disappointed about the bill,
但不得不說  我鬆了口氣
but I have to say, I'm relieved.
你還好吧
How are you holding up?
你聽說凱瑟琳做了什麼嗎  許諾馮政治避難
Did you hear what Catherine did? Giving Feng asylum?
不可原諒
Inexcusable.
加勒特氣瘋了  他覺得走投無路
Garrett's beside himself. He feels cornered,
這下我們除了放棄保密權別無選擇
like we have no choice but to waive the privileges now.
藥物的事呢
But what about the medication?
可不是啊  我不該說的
I know. I shouldn't be sharing this.
不說了  你該走了
We don't have to talk about it. You should go.
我知道你日程排得很滿
I know you have a packed schedule.
謝謝你這麼做
Thank you for doing this.
我只是在走廊裡單獨找上了她
All I had to do was get her alone in a hallway.
我是說傑姬那邊
I meant with Jackie.
我們要分清輕重緩急
We have our priorities.
我知道做這樣的放棄並不容易
Well, I know it isn't easy to let go of something like that.
答應我一件事
Promise me something.
你說吧
Anything.
我不能一個人住在這房子裡
I can't live in this house alone.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你是這麼說  但這事可能事與願違
You say that, but this could all backfire.
雷蒙德肯定會拒不解釋
Raymond will plead the Fifth.
如果他提到我  便是承認有罪了
If he names me, it's an admission of his own wrongdoing.
我更擔心加勒特
I'm more worried about Garrett.
你製造了一個有力的對手
You've made a powerful enemy.
我們比他們強
We're stronger than they are.
可他仍然是總統
And he's still the president.
我向你保證  你被迫做出的一切犧牲之中
I promise you, of all of the sacrifices that you've had to make,
絕不會包括與一名罪犯離婚
divorcing a convict will not be one of them.
我們不能放棄保密權  加勒特
We can't waive the privileges, Garrett.
我們沒別的選擇了  馮承認了那筆錢
Well, we don't have a choice anymore. Feng confirmed the money.
在電話上承認的  不是當面正式承認的
Over the phone. Not in a formal interview.
解除對他的庇護  送他回去
Rescind the asylum. Send him back --
妨礙司法公正
Obstruction of justice.
嘉利克這麼說的嗎
Is that what Galich said?
別人肯定會這麼想
Definitely how it would be perceived.
我們任何不配合調查的舉動
And anything we do that looks like a failure to cooperate
都會加重他們的猜疑
amplifies that perception.
我只是不想公開我們的婚姻問題
I just don't want our marriage put on display.
鄧巴會問我是否提及過中國  我沒有
Look, Dunbar'll ask if I brought up China. I didn't.
拉金能證明我的清白
So Larkin can only help to exonerate me.
如果婚姻諮詢最終進入報告  也無所謂
And if the marriage counseling ends up in the report, so be it.
我們能渡過這個難關
We can survive that.
但他給我們開了處方藥
But he prescribed us medication.
不算是我們
Technically not us.
你在吃我的藥  加勒特
You took mine, Garrett.
拉金知道你會吃才給我開的藥
Larkin wrote the prescription to me knowing you would.
等等  你提過了  處方藥的事
Wait, wait, have you mentioned it? The medication?
跟克萊爾嗎
Claire?
對不起  我只能跟她傾訴
I'm sorry. But she's the only person I can talk to
只有她能理解
who really understands what it's like --
那我們更要放棄保密權了
Oh, all the more reason we have to waive the privilege.
如果他們洩露出去  就由不得我們做主了
If they leak this, we can't control the information.
克萊爾不會那麼做的
Claire wouldn't do that.
不要小看她
Don't underestimate her.
他們要是真準備這麼做  現在不早做了
If they were going to, don't you think they would have done it by now?
她為了減少我們的負擔  放棄了性侵法案
She dropped the sexual assault bill to reduce pressure on us.
她也許是這麼跟你說的
That may have been what she told you.
他們什麼都不會說的
They're not going to say anything.
我求你了  加勒特
I'm begging you, Garrett.
不要放棄保密權
Don't waive the privilege.
我們談論的事太私密了
The things we talked about were so intimate.
如果孩子們看到
Imagine if the kids --
我知道  但是特莉莎
I know. But Tricia --
我們競選的時候
When we ran,
我知道我們的生活將被人仔細審視
I knew every aspect of our lives would be under scrutiny.
但我覺得我們至少還能保護這個
But I thought we could protect at least this.
發生在這裡的事
What happens in here.
我會不惜一切保護我們
I'll protect us. Whatever I have to do.
你要相信我
You have to believe that.
我們檢查了USB軟體狗
We checked the USB dongle.
你聲稱感染了資訊中心的程式碼不在裡面
The code you're claiming infected the data center isn't there.
我設計那段程式碼一到達伺服器便自我刪除
I programmed the code to self-erase as soon as it hit the server.
在盧卡斯被捕之前就不見了
It was gone before Lucas was in cuffs.
你信不過我
You don't believe me?
這可是世上最複雜的防火牆之一
This is one of the most sophisticated firewalls in the world.
就算真的進去了  也破壞不了
Even if your code did get in there, you couldn't break it down.
你妻子手機的運營商就是他們公司
Your wife uses AT&T.
她情人也是
So does her lover.
什麼
What?
她現在就在那兒  喬納森·坎普
She's over there right now. Jonathan Kemp.
她的脊椎按摩師  對嗎
It's her chiropractor, right?
想看看他們互發的簡訊嗎
Want to see their texts to each other?
不想
No.
看來你早就知道了
Oh, I see you already know.
我理解你不想把事情鬧大
I don't blame you for not making a fuss,
畢竟孩子們還在家裡
what with the kids still at home.
但你讓我的程式碼進了那扇門
But you walked my code right through that door.
進入了三千兩百萬人的手機裡
Into 32 million people's phones.
這都怪你
And that's on you.
聯調局也罪責難逃  這會鬧得很難看
And it's on the FBI. And it is a shit-storm
讓聯調局面臨國會的調查
that will bring the Bureau right in front of Congress.
所以你告訴我  平息這一切要多大代價
So you tell me: How much is making that disappear worth?
你面臨一百年的監禁
You have a hundred years hanging over your head.
敲詐聯調局對你沒好處
Extorting the FBI won't help you.
是道格拉斯·斯坦普讓你陷害盧卡斯·古德溫的嗎
Did Douglas Stamper tell you to set up Lucas Goodwin?
反恐主管
Counter-Terrorism Director.
跟白宮聯絡官相比真是一步登天
That's a big step up from White House Liaison.
-我認為你背後有推手    -胡說
- I think you had a helping hand.   - Not true.
繼續編  但以下是我的要求
Keep lying. Meanwhile, here's what I want.
第一  我不再是你的走狗了
One, I'm no longer your bitch.
第二  撤銷對我的所有指控
Two, all of my charges are dropped.
第三  撤銷所有對巴利特·布朗的指控
Three, all of Barrett Brown's charges are dropped.
這得看聯邦檢察官的
That's up to the U.S. Attorney.
你去想辦法
Figure it out.
如果我聽得沒錯
If I'm hearing you correctly,
你是想要拉金的證詞
you'd like to keep Larkin's testimony
側重在洗錢上
focused on the money laundering.
而我從來沒提過  因為我毫不知情
Which I never brought up, because I knew nothing about it.
但你擔心其他的事  私人的事
But your concern is other matters. Private matters.
這些和調查無關
Which are irrelevant to the investigation.
我不能阻止鄧巴問問題
I can't prevent Dunbar from asking what she's gonna ask.
當然不能
Of course not.
我最多只能去拜托拉金博士
The most I can do is ask Dr. Larkin
跟他對下部分問題的回答
how he would respond to certain questions.
但他很聰明  會明白我的目的
But he's a smart man. He'll understand what I'm getting at.
這路子合法嗎
And this approach keeps us within the law?
沒有干擾證詞嗎
We're not tampering with testimony?
界線很模糊  但我會確保合法
It's a fine line. But I'll stay on the right side of it.
他不見我  弗蘭克  就像他對你一樣
He shut me out, Frank. Just like he did with you.
我的副國務卿被委派了全權外交權
My undersecretary has been assigned full diplomatic authority.
暫時的挫折  凱茜  我到哪你到哪
A temporary setback, Cathy. Where I go, you go.
現在總統正在戰況室
At this very moment, the President is in the Situation Room.
中方對馮的政治庇護的反應跟我預想的一樣
China responded to Feng's asylum exactly the way I predicted.
他們增派了一倍海軍前往與那國島
They're doubling their naval presence off the coast of Yonaguni.
你猜誰被趕出戰況室了  你和我  弗蘭克
And you know who isn't in the Situation Room? You and I, Frank.
你只盯著眼下一時的得失
You're thinking about where we are
卻對情勢的發展方向視而不見
instead of where we're headed.
這可不像那個在傑斐遜舞會上
Now that isn't the Catherine Durant
和我共舞華爾茲的凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
that I waltzed with at the Jefferson Ball.
她深明大勢所趨
She understood potential.
她盯著未來
She had her eyes toward the future.
我對那個凱瑟琳·杜蘭特說
I told that Catherine Durant
我們需要她這樣的人領導國務院
that we needed her in the State Department.
現在也是如此  真不知她哪去了
We still need her. I wish I knew where she was,
因為她和我眼前這個凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
because she is not the Catherine Durant
完全是兩種人
sitting in front of me right now.
但我跟你說
But I'll tell you something,
如果她不趕快回來的話
If she doesn't show up soon, well,
那這支華爾茲  我只好獨自舞下去了
I'm just gonna have to keep waltzing alone.
因為我已經
Because I am done trying to
不想再去說服我面前的這個女人
convince this woman in front of me
和我攜手前行了
to take my arm.
你快忙去吧  我不留你了
Oh, don't let me keep you.
我就在這兒  我哪也不去  弗蘭克
I'm here. I'm not going anywhere, Frank.
你現在能拿到總統簡報嗎
You still have access to the presidential briefing?
能  就在我手上
Yes, I have it right here.
跟我說說與中國之間的全部情況
Walk me through everything that's going on with China.
馮也出場了  也許我們用得上他
Feng is in play now. We might be able to use him.
怎麼用
How?
我還不知道
I don't know yet.
但顯然他在北京眼裡是有價值的
But he's clearly valuable to Beijing,
那麼他對我們就也有價值
which makes him valuable to us.
從沒提起過馮山德嗎
Nothing about Xander Feng?
沒有
Never.
丹尼爾·拉尼根呢  還有雷蒙德·塔斯克
Daniel Lanagin? Raymond Tusk?
我們只談了他的婚姻
We only discussed their marriage.
從未涉及白宮的公務
Nothing about the business of the White House.
他可曾間接提起過與工作有關的壓力
Any oblique reference to work-related pressures he was feeling?
他說他現在睡眠太少
He said he wasn't getting as much sleep as he'd like.
你給他開過什麼藥物嗎
Did you ever prescribe him any medication?
正如我一貫聲稱  我只提供宗教諮詢
As I've always stated, I provided religious counsel.
我明白  但我問的是藥物處方
I understand. But I'm asking about medication.
這有什麼關係嗎
How is this relevant?
我想查證他的判斷力是否因此受影響
I'm trying to assess whether his judgment may have been impaired.
在我看來  他和他的妻子
In my opinion, he and his wife
面對的是典型的婚姻問題
were dealing with standard marital issues.
你這是答非所問  拉金博士
That's not what I asked, Dr. Larkin.
所以我再問第三遍
So I will ask for a third time.
而且問得更明確些
And let me be more specific.
美利堅合眾國總統
Was any medication prescribed
在接受你的諮詢服務時  你是否提供過
or taken as a result of your counseling session
任何形式的處方或者藥物
by the President of the United States?
他的工作能力完全沒有受影響
His faculties were operating at a hundred percent,
如果你是想問這個的話
if that's what you're asking.
是不是有政府方面的人和你談過了
Has anyone from the administration spoken to you?
什麼意思
How do you mean?
關於取證  是不是有人找過你  指導過你
About this deposition. Has anyone approached you, coached you?
如果你現在承認  我會將此認定為及時申報
If you tell me now, I will qualify that as a timely declaration.
我不想繼續了
I'd like to leave.
總統放棄了他的保密權利
The President waived his privilege.
但我是自願作證的
But I'm here voluntarily.
拉金博士  一開始你不肯作證
Dr. Larkin, at first you wouldn't talk to me
因為那有違你的道德準則
because it violated your ethical code.
我尊重你的選擇
I respect that.
但現在我要問你  作為一個虔誠之人
But let me ask you, as a man of faith
蓄意對我說謊  難道就不違反你的道德準則嗎
is deliberately lying to me an exception to that code?
因為你拒絕說出實情的話
Because that is what you're doing
就有作偽證的嫌疑
by refusing to share the truth.
我不明白
I don't understand.
這法案過不了的
It wasn't going to pass.
但你說我們就要爭取到足夠的支援了
But you said we almost had the votes.
我們需要能完全確定  但實情並非如此
We needed to be a hundred percent solid, and we weren't.
如果法案未能通過  我們的努力就白費了
If the bill failed, that would set us back.
我們必須接受漸進的改革方案
We need to accept incremental reform.
你的口氣跟傑姬·夏普一模一樣
You sound just like Jackie Sharp.
其實我現在與她合作了
I'm actually working with her now.
她是一個有力的盟友
She's a powerful ally for us to have.
可她那樣讓我下不來臺
After what she did to me?
還公開羞辱你
After what she said about you?
我要是被他人的非議所左右
If I let the things people say about me get under my skin,
我連家門都出不去了
I wouldn't be able to leave my own home.
你知道結果會怎樣
You know how this will go.
人人都會說"太好了  我們取得了成功"
Everyone will say, "Great, we did something,"
但其實一無所成
Which is really nothing.
他們會高興一時  然後就拋諸腦後忘個乾淨
They'll pat themselves on the back and they'll forget about it.
我們讓人們注意這個話題了
We helped put this on the radar.
我以為我們是要真正改變現狀
I thought we were doing something real.
改變人們的生活  幼稚死了  對吧
Changing people's lives. How naive, right?
但至少我不願意放棄
But at least I didn't want to give up.
也許傑姬·夏普說對了
Maybe Jackie Sharp is right.
你他媽就是個懦夫
You are a fucking coward.
是我鼓勵你站出來說出你的遭遇
I'm the one that pulled you out from under the covers.
之前你在逃避  靠吃藥度日
You were hiding. You and your pills.
編造各種謊言自欺欺人
So you tell yourself whatever you need to.
我失態了
I'm sorry.
有些政治現實  是我們無法忽視的
There were political realities we couldn't ignore.
你想沒想過為什麼那麼多人憎恨華盛頓
Do you ever wonder why so many people hate Washington?
就是因為你這種人說那種屁話
It's because of people like you using phrases like that.
雷蒙德
Raymond?
雖說該開燈  但既然花錢住進
I'd turn the lights on, but when you're paying for the room
風景最好的房間  就不如欣賞個夠
with the best view you might as well make the most of it.
我從來沒上過頂層  你呢
I've never been in the penthouse here. Have you?
這是什麼情況
What's going on?
你知道我為什麼來華盛頓嗎
Do you know why I'm in D.C.?
沒關係  雷米
Oh, it's okay, Remy.
你能說出的話我都已經知道了
There's nothing you can say that I don't already know.
馮要去作證了
Feng is on his way to testify.
不管賽斯跟你說了什麼都不要信他
Whatever Seth has told you, don't believe a word of it.
他會說什麼我不該相信的事呢
What might he have told me that I shouldn't believe?
你跟副總統見面了
You met with the Vice President.
在一座教堂裡  別裝作沒這回事
In a church. Don't pretend you didn't.
想當牆頭草嗎
Playing both sides?
雷蒙德  我...
Raymond, look --
我想聽你說出來  你跟弗蘭克見面了
I want to hear you say it. That you met with Frank.
我會跟你說的  雷蒙德  但他不能在這兒
I'll talk to you, Raymond, but not with him here.
你先出去吧
Leave us.
要我在電梯裡等你嗎
Should I hold the elevator for you?
滾你媽的
Go fuck yourself.
好  那你走樓梯吧
Okay. You can take the stairs.
他們在耍你  雷蒙德
They're toying with you, Raymond.
沒錯  但是你也一樣  雷米
No doubt. But so are you, Remy.
我是想哄騙弗蘭克  讓他以為已經安全了
I wanted to lead Frank on, give him a false sense of security.
如果你要說謊  那就說得漂亮點
If you're gonna lie, lie better than that.
他們想離間我們
They want to tear us apart.
你想要多條退路  這我不怪你
I don't blame you for wanting to keep your options open.
但你顯然買錯了保險
But clearly you have bought the wrong insurance policy.
不要這樣搬起石頭砸自己的腳
Don't shoot yourself in the foot like this.
你的腳  石頭也是你拿著呢
Your foot. And you're holding the gun.
去找個別的地方流血吧
Now go someplace else to bleed.
你想談談流血嗎
You want to talk about blood?
你與弗蘭克的這場戰爭已經讓你流了多少血了
How much have you spilt in this war with Frank?
我做的一切都是為了維護和平
All I've tried to do is keep the peace.
你本可讓他佔上風
You could've let him have the upper hand.
除了你的自尊  還會讓你損失什麼
What would that have really cost you, other than your pride?
真遺憾
Such a shame.
你剛剛樹立了身家420億的敵人  雷米
You have just made 42 billion enemies, Remy.
外加一些零頭
And some change.
390億  雷蒙德  你的市值在縮水
39 billion, Raymond. Your market cap is shrinking.
白宮顧問比爾·嘉利克今早被特別檢查官
White House Counsel Bill Galich was called into questioning this morning
比爾·嘉利克
希瑟·鄧巴傳喚質詢
by Special Prosecutor Heather Dunbar.
從鄧巴辦公室得到的訊息稱
According to Dunbar's office,
他們懷疑
there are suspicions that
嘉利克可能干預了證人證詞
Galich may have tampered with witness testimony.
這名證人是托馬斯·拉金博士
The witness in question is Dr. Thomas Larkin,
一位牧師與諮詢師
a reverend and therapist
據稱他為總統和第一夫人進行了
who allegedly conducted secret marriage counseling sessions
祕密婚姻諮詢
for the president and first lady.
如果沒有來自總統的明確指示
The White House counsel wouldn't be manipulating testimony
白宮顧問是不會去干預證詞的
without explicit direction from the Oval Office.
同樣讓人不安的是  我們的總統
And just as disconcerting is the fact that our president
在尋求心理治療
is seeking psychological treatment
並且向美國人民隱瞞這一點
and chose to hide this from the American people.
如果在這方面我們無法信任他
If we can't trust him about that,
那我們又怎麼知道他是否與洗錢陰謀有關呢
then how do we know he wasn't involved in a money-laundering scheme?
怎麼知道他的精神狀況適合來領導我們呢
How do we know he's mentally fit to lead?
最重要的是  如果他知法犯法
And most important, how can he enforce the law
又如何維護法律
when he's breaking it?
我認為我們眾議院的同事
I believe our colleagues in the House certainly have enough
已經有足夠理由考慮彈劾
to consider Articles of Impeachment.
信任與法律都被踐踏
Both trust and laws have been broken.
不管眾議院作何打算
Whatever the House decides to do,
這位總統必須承擔責任
we must hold this president accountable.
全力支援總統
Fully support the president
不管發生什麼都跟他站在一起
and will stand by him no matter what comes his way.
攬進來  處理掉  給我找艾拉·薩伊德
Put that in, put it out. Then get me Ayla Sayyad.
至於雷米  讓他再多倒黴一陣子吧
And as for Remy, let's let him wither on the vine a little longer.
同時  讓他的另一半明天來眾議院
In the meantime, have his better half come by the house tomorrow.
雷蒙德
Raymond?
不  傑姬
No. Jackie.
塔斯克先生
Mr. Tusk.
鄧巴女士  我活了67年
Well, Ms. Dunbar, in 67 years on this planet
還從來沒被傳喚過
I have never once been issued a subpoena.
現在總算可以從遺願清單上劃掉了
I can now cross that off my bucket list.
此次會面將被記錄和封存
This interview is being recorded and sealed.
如傳票所述  塔斯克先生  我與馮山德談過了
As the subpoena mentioned, Mr. Tusk, I spoke with Xander Feng.
他指證你與他合作  自2005年以來
He verified that you were his partner
將中國資金洗白並流入超級政治行動委員會
in laundering Chinese money to political Super PACs since 2005.
你如何迴應他的指控
How would you respond to his allegations?
我的客戶要行使憲法第五修正案賦予的權利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
你是否曾用這些捐贈來換取政治利益
Did you ever use these contributions to bargain for political favors?
我的客戶要行使憲法第五修正案賦予的權利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
你跟丹尼爾·拉尼根是什麼關係
What was your relationship with Daniel Lanagin?
我的客戶要行使憲法第五修正案賦予的權利
My client exercises his right to plead the Fifth Amendment.
我都記不得我為什麼要來這兒了
I don't even remember why I came over here.
你是說你最初來我家嗎
You mean when you first showed up?
不  我是說來廚房
No. To the kitchen.
很抱歉  別認為我不愛你
I'm sorry. Please don't think that I don't love you --
那是為什麼  我不明白
Then why? I don't get it.
一切發展得太快了
Everything's been so fast.
還有
And...
我不知道  很難說清  但我還沒準備好
I don't know. It's hard to explain, but I'm not ready for this.
-都是胡說    -不是的
- That's bullshit.   - No, it's not.
我還在努力適應新生活
I'm still trying to figure out this new life.
這一切太讓人搞不清
And this is too confusing.
只有這是清清楚楚的  這你知道
This is the only thing that's clear, and you know it.
你在害怕  但這是好事
You're afraid, but it's good to be afraid when you're--
你得離開  為了你自己好
I need you to leave, okay? For your own good.
我只會傷害你
I am just gonna hurt you.
我比你想得堅韌得多
I have thicker skin than you can even imagine.
別把事情搞得太痛苦
Please don't make this harder than it has to be.
昨天一切都還好好的  這麼突然
Everything was fine yesterday. It's so sudden.
簡直莫名其妙
It's like it's coming out of nowhere.
不是這樣  我已經考慮了一段時間了
Well, it's not. I've been thinking about it for a while.
你沒有  否則我會察覺的
No, you haven't. I would have sensed it.
能不能請你  拜託你走就是了
Would you please, please, please just go?
告訴我發生了什麼事
Just tell me what's going on.
我不指望你會理解
I don't expect you to understand.
也許你可以試著...
Well, maybe if you try --
我不想讓你待在這兒  好嗎
I don't want you here. Okay?
我不像你愛我那樣愛著你
I don't love you the way that you love me.
只是利用你  因為有你陪著感覺很好
I was using you because it felt good to have you around,
但那樣很自私
but it was selfish.
我說那些話  因為我知道你愛聽
I said the words because I knew you wanted to hear 'em,
但我不是真心的
but I didn't mean 'em.
我不想繼續說下去了
And I don't want to keep saying 'em.
我出去走一會兒  你收拾東西吧
I'm gonna go for a walk while you pack your stuff.
不  我不要這兒的任何東西
No. I don't want anything that's been here.
麗薩
Lisa...?
"四面的山窪霧氣氤氳
"There was a steaming mist in all the hollows,
淒涼地往山頂湧動
and it roamed in its forlornness up the hill,
雙城記
彷彿是個邪惡的精靈  尋找歇腳之地而不得
like an evil spirit, seeking rest and finding none.
那霧粘乎乎的  冰寒徹骨
A clammy, and intensely cold mist,
緩緩地在空中波浪式地翻滾
it made it its slow way through the air in ripples
一浪一浪清晰可見  然後宛如汙濁的海濤
that visibly followed and overspread one another,
搞定了
彼此滲誘  融合成了一片
as the waves of an unwholesome sea might do.
霧很濃  車燈幾乎
It was dense enough to shut out everything
什麼也照不見"
from the light of the coach lamps."
很驚訝你想和我聊聊
I'm surprised you wanted to speak to me.
我並不是很受政府歡迎
I haven't been the biggest friend of the administration.
難道不是找你談話的最佳理由嗎
Isn't that the very best reason to speak with you?
我想開始錄音
I'd like to begin recording.
請便
By all means.
許多政治分析家預測
A number of political analysts predict
眾議院司法委員會
that the House Judiciary Committee
將就彈劾條款開始聽證會
will commence with hearings on Articles of Impeachment.
先就此打住
Let's just stop right there.
你說的這些分析家
So these analysts you speak of,
他們在鄧巴的報告發表前就做出預測
they're making predictions prior to Dunbar's report even being released.
報告出來可能得好幾個月
That could take months.
司法委員會絕不會等那麼久的
There's no way the Judiciary will sit on this for that long.
這不正是聽證會的根本問題嗎
And isn't that the fundamental flaw with these hearings?
因為包括你在內的媒體記者提出的假設
The committee feels compelled to act because of hypotheses
委員會覺得必須採取行動
advanced by those in the media, such as yourself.
我不能代表我所有的同行  但我只是報導事實
I can't speak for all of my colleagues, but I'm just reporting facts.
你可能會說這是事實  但實話說
Well, you may call them facts, but if we're being honest,
-難道不是    -每篇文章和採訪中
- aren't they just --   - In every article and interview,
我都只是提出懷疑
I report alleged activities.
懷疑重複的次數夠多
And if you repeat allegations enough,
一遍一遍  反反覆覆
again and over and over and over,
那就三人成虎了  這是人之常情
people start to believe that they're true. That's human nature.
我做過調查
I've done my research.
馮山德已經承認洗錢
Xander Feng admitted to the money laundering.
但你已經不報導馮山德了  對嗎
But you're no longer writing about Xander Feng. Are you?
你現在報導政府
You're writing about the administration.
事實上  聽證會就是由媒體報導引發的
The truth is, these hearings have been initiated by the press.
我擔心的是總統會遭到媒體的審判
And my fear is that the president will be tried by the press.
你相信他是無罪的嗎
Do you believe he's innocent?
絕對
Absolutely.
我在書面聲明中這麼寫  我現在也還要這麼說
I said so in my written statement and I say so again now.
白宮的法律顧問已經否認了干預拉金博士的證詞
The White House counsel has denied coaching Dr. Larkin,
-但根據...    -不管最終發現了什麼
- but according to Ms. --   - Whatever comes to light,
都只會證明總統的清白
it will only prove the president's innocence.
我告訴你為什麼  加勒特·沃克是我所認識的
And I'll tell you why. I have never known anyone more honest,
最誠實  正直  愛國的人
ethical, and patriotic than Garrett Walker.
他對我國憲法和法律的尊重
His reverence for the Constitution and the laws of this country
無人能及
are surpassed by none.
特莉莎和我有幸擁有一段堅固忠誠的婚姻
Tricia and I have been blessed with a strong and loving marriage.
但再堅固的婚姻也會面臨挑戰
But even strong marriages face challenges.
就像成百萬的美國人一樣
Like millions of Americans,
我們向一位宗教導師尋求建議
we sought counseling from a spiritual advisor,
而他恰好也是一位職業治療師
one who happened also to be a professional therapist.
多年來我們經常
Over the years we have often
在困境中向我們的信仰尋求幫助
turned to our faith in times of adversity.
很多人批評我們
Many have criticized us.
但你們寧願要一位不去尋求幫助的總統嗎
But would you rather have a president that doesn't ask for help?
我每一天都會請我妻子幫我
I ask for help from my wife every day.
我們相扶相依已經有23年了
We've relied on one another for 23 years.
我們一起養育了兩個漂亮的孩子
We've raised two beautiful children together.
華爾街電訊報  副總統維護總統
一起走過了競選之旅
Endured the campaign trails together.
從州首府丹佛
From the state capital in Denver
一路來到國家首都
to the nation's capital,
我們一直都在彼此身邊
we've always been at each other's side.
我嫁給這個人的原因
I married this man for the
和你們很多人選他的原因一樣
same reason that so many of you voted for him.
因為他是一位信徒  因為他熱愛家人
Because he's a man of God. Because he believes in family.
因為他有同情心和愛心
Because he is compassionate and loving.
人無完人
Now, none of us are perfect.
我不是  特莉莎也不是
I'm not. Tricia's not.
儘管她很接近完美了
Although she certainly comes close.
早上好  馮先生
Good morning, Mr. Feng.
我不會否認我作為凡人的極限
I won't ignore what makes me human.
否則只是盲目
That's a form of blindness.
好的領導者應該正視自己的缺點
Good leadership means tackling my imperfections head on.
對一個在逃亡的人來說不錯嘛
Not bad for a man on the run.
你是說對一個有豁免權的人來說
You mean a man with immunity.
隨便你想怎麼說了
Wherever you're most comfortable.
我們有很多事要談
We have a lot to discuss.
我是在瞭解情況的前提下這麼做的
I do so with open eyes.
我的愛也是明明白白的
Just as I love, with open eyes,
愛我的妻子  愛上帝
my wife, my maker,
愛我的國家
and my country.
請進
Come in.
謝謝  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
傑姬  一般來說
Jackie, in these circumstances
我會去找你
normally I would come to you,
但現在我們還是保持距離為好
but we need to keep a public distance for the time being.
我以為我是來討論性侵法案的
I thought I was here to discuss the sexual assault bill.
是的  還有其他的事
You are. Among other things.
明白了
I see.
你有條件
There's a price.
不要這樣說
Well, we don't think of it that way.
不管今天你說什麼
I'm going to support your bill,
我都會支援你的法案
no matter what you say today.
什麼事
Regarding?
彈劾
Impeachment.
如果事情真鬧到司法委員會
Well, if it goes to the Judiciary --
幾乎肯定是會的
It most definitely will.
我不那麼肯定
I'm not sure about that.
你們看了總統的聲明瞭嗎
Did you see the president's address?
我們看了
We did.
我覺得能起些作用  控制事態
I think it will help. Stop the bleeding.
而且彈劾可以被否決
Impeachment can be defeated.
但那是我們要避免的
But that's we need to avoid.
你希望彈劾
You want impeachment...
為什麼要打一場明知會輸的仗
Why fight a losing battle?
我們在眾議院是多數黨
We have a majority in the House.
現在是
We do now.
但如果本黨不能和一個汙點總統
But if this party fails to distance itself
劃清界限
from a toxic president...
我們在做長遠打算
We're thinking ahead here.
所以我才會找你就法案的事和解
It's why I came to you about the bill.
我們不值得為它翻臉
Because it wasn't worth burning a bridge over.
長遠來講  我們合作的好處更多
In the long run we have a lot more to gain by working together.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你在《電訊報》採訪的時候說你會
You said in the Telegraph article that you would sta--
我必須那麼說
I had to.
我的辦公室跟總統的只隔了三間屋子
My office is three doors down from the president's.
我不能公開詆譭他
I can't publicly deride him.
你希望我來做
You want me to do it?
我們希望你做你最拿手的  拉選票
We want you to do what you do so well: whip the votes.
我不能背叛總統
I can't abandon the president.
如果這個黨救了他
If the party rescues him,
我們將在中期選舉時失去50個席位
we'll lose 50 seats in the House in the midterms.
你會失去你在領導層的地位
You will lose your position in the leadership.
我們要花十年
And it will take us a decade
重新贏得選民的信任
to regain the trust of the electorate.
我們只求你肯聽取意見
All we're asking is that you have an open mind.
克萊爾就是如此
Claire kept an open mind,
你得以修改性侵法案
and you'll pass sexual assault reform as a result.
你不能把彈劾和...
You can't possibly compare impeachment to --
只是舉個例子  傑姬
It's an illustration, Jackie.
說明未來會怎麼樣
Of what the future looks like.
我們提出的  是進步
What we offer is progress.
並保證日後還會有更多進步
With a promise of more to come.
這隻是個開始  傑姬
It's only the beginning, Jackie.
堅決  務實  記得嗎
Ruthless pragmatism, remember?
所以我才選你做黨鞭
That's why I wanted you to be the whip.
我們三個是同一類人
The three of us, we're cut from the same cloth.
副總統先生
Mr. Vice President,
你要我做的  幾乎是叛國
what you're asking is just shy of treason.
幾乎  也就是政治
Just shy. Which is politics.
小心  那很易碎
Be careful. It's delicate.
這是什麼
What is it?
一件我做了很久的事
Something I've been working on for a very long time.
馬上就要完成了
And it's nearly finished.
傑姬
Jackie?
幫我們完成吧
Help us finish it.
■
美國法律規定  在總統或其他政府要員  聯邦法官
出現重大工作失誤  或有嚴重違法嫌疑時
國會有權行使彈劾權力  彈劾程式啟動後
首先要求眾議院投票  簡單多數通過彈劾決議後
再由參議院進行表決
但是只有在參議院2/3的多數投贊成票後
彈劾才會生效
以防止兩黨以彈劾作為政治鬥爭的武器
■
雖然美國歷史上許多總統在任期間曾爆出醜聞
但是國會真正啟動彈劾程式只有兩次
1868年  國會以違反行政任命法為由
投票彈劾時任總統安德魯·傑克遜
但是在參議院投票時  一票之差
彈劾案沒有獲得所需的2/3多數
第二次彈劾程式啟動要等到一百多年之後
在上世紀90年代  總統克林頓深陷萊溫斯基醜聞
在國會佔有多數席位的共和黨啟動彈劾程式
但是同樣沒有獲得足夠票數  克林頓涉險過關
由於他任職期間美國經濟高速發展
所以雖然醜聞纏身  但是克林頓民意支援率一直很高
在人們所熟知的水門事件中  沒有啟動彈劾程式
在國會考慮進行彈劾前  尼克森總統便已經宣佈辭職